<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grabbing Data on My blog</title>
    <link>https://srdasara.github.io/tags/grabbing-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grabbing Data on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://srdasara.github.io/tags/grabbing-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring data from NASA Earth-observing satellites for Southern Ocean-scale analysis</title>
      <link>https://srdasara.github.io/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srdasara.github.io/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important and time-consuming steps in conducting spatiotemporal analyses, ESPECIALLY that which uses satellite data, is to get these data, convert it into readable format, and confirm that the arrays are in the correct format, layout, etc. for further imaging and statistical processing. Without a doubt, in all of the analyses I&amp;rsquo;ve conducted, this has been the steepest learning curve, and even required an internship at NASA Langley to colloborate on how best to define calculation of new variables from raw data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southern Ocean-scale seasonal analysis</title>
      <link>https://srdasara.github.io/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srdasara.github.io/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Before I qualified and moved forward to PhD Candidacy, I wanted to examine what happens if I do the earlier study across the entire Southern Ocean. Here I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled my code &amp;amp; figures for some preliminary data analysis mimicking methods from the earlier manuscript but zoomed out to the entire Southern Ocean.
Variables assessed include marine aerosol optical depth (MAOD), depolarization ratio (sea ice), chlorophyll-a concentration, and wind speed. This research is still in the works, but what is interesting is that spatial clustering of MAOD &amp;amp; sea ice, MAOD &amp;amp; wind speed, and sea ice &amp;amp; chlorophyll-a concentration is significant, also seen in and supporting the prior study!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
